ANDREW BERNHARDT

(NÉ KOLOKOLNIKOV)

+358 50 447 1522

andrew@ab2b.io

00400 Helsinki, Finland

FULL-STACK HR PROFESSIONAL

10+ years building top-performing teams in high-growth tech companies and startups.

I believe in a holistic approach to People Operations and enabling businesses to achieve set goals via talent. My values are kindness, empathy, curiosity, leading by example, ownership, and getting it done.

EXPERIENCE

Nightingale Health

Talent Partner

2023-2024

Performance management, organizational design, and talent acquisition.

Rive (Kodit.io) 2021-2023

Chief People Officer

- Enabled team growth from 60 to 340 (including M&A support).
- HR Strategy, Operational HR, and HR Business Partnership (Finland, Spain, Poland).
- Compensation and Leveling (ESOP + salary), R&R, Payroll, Benefits, HR compliance.
- Performance Management, Organizational Structure, On/off-boarding, and L&D.
- OKRs, KPIs, and reporting across the organization.
- HR toolkit implementation: HRMS, ATS, payroll, and time-tracking.
- Change negotiations (Tietotekniikan palvelualan työehtosopimus & employment law).

MaaS Global (Whim)

2023-2024

Head of Talent Acquisition

- Led the Compensation and Levelling framework establishment in the company.
- Initiated and ran the cross-organizational L&D project: Leadership Academy.
- Built the TA function from the ground up.

ANDREW BERNHARDT

(NÉ KOLOKOLNIKOV)

+358 50 447 1522

andrew@ab2b.io

00400 Helsinki, Finland

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Yousician 2015-2019

Talent Business Partner, Human Resources Lead

• Early employee. Established and led the People function to build and evolve a high-performing team from 35 to 70 people.

• Partnered with and coached team leads on HR matters: Onboarding, Performance Management, Learning and Development, People Analytics, and Culture.

Sampo Accelerator

ongoing

Coach

• Leadership, trust, psychological safety, belonging, commitment, & team performance.

SKILLS

- Leadership
- Team management
- Public speaking
- Performance management
- Rewards & Recognition
- Employment law & compliance
- People Analytics
- Tools implementation
- Payroll

EDUCATION

BBA, Bachelor of Business Administration

2008-2013

International Business and Logistics, Metropolia University of Applied Sciences

Exchange studies: Kwantlen Polytechnic University, Vancouver, Canada

Master's Degree, Economics & Management

2002-2007

Moscow Automobile and Road Construction State Technical University

Major: Business / Managerial Economics

ANDREW BERNHARDT

(NÉ KOLOKOLNIKOV)

+358 50 447 1522

andrew@ab2b.io

00400 Helsinki, Finland

REFERENCES



Chris Thür · 1st CEO at Yousician

March 21, 2024, Chris managed Andrew directly

I've worked with Andrew for many years at Yousician both as team member and him reporting to me. Andrew is a very unique individual that brings enthusiasm and excitement to anything he does. He's great at connecting with people, listening to them and a fast learner. I greatly admire his ability to be both professional and personal, be encouraging/inspiring and stern in feedback, have patience but also drive with people. Andrew is both a starter, driving new initiatives with enthusiasm and an open mind, and a closer, getting things over the finish line with little formal supervision. I hope we work together one day again!



Jeffrey Barrett in . 1st

Chief Scientific Officer, Nightingale Health

March 21, 2024, Jeffrey was senior to Andrew but didn't manage Andrew directly

Andrew did a great job recruiting new talent to Nightingale. I really enjoyed working with him because he ran a very smooth process, and communicated well both with applicants and the internal hiring team. I'd warmly recommend him to anyone looking to build high performing teams.



Iñaki Crespo · 1st

CPTO @ Rive

March 21, 2024, Iñaki worked with Andrew on the same team

Andrew knows what he has to do and gets it done. Extremely talented + Mindful human always available to help.

I can proudly say that I would partner with Andrew for anything.